Kia ora shou shi ku wa
Quiet on the set
Quiet, please
First position, please
Rolling, action!
Hello everyone and welcome to Director's Cut
My name is Marco and I'm joined here with
Bill
Hello
Bill, win
I don't, I wouldn't rather
You don't reveal that information
You don't want me to say it last night?
No, it's okay, I'm just kidding
Alright, and also with us
is a new member to the English pod team
Jay
Hello
And Jay is working with us now
and she's originally from Canada
What about from Canada are you from?
From the East Coast
The East Coast, right?
From Canada
East side
Hey
Alright, and on this edition of Director's Cut
we're going to talk about the movie Watchmen
Yes
Have you seen that movie?
I have, well, I, yeah, I have seen it
Did you like it?
Yeah, I really did like it
Why?
Um, geez, that's a pretty open-ended question
for the beginning of the show
I can't even remember what happened
I liked it because the alternate reality aspect of it
You know, I think it had more of a science fiction
kind of feel to it than most comic book movies
Um, I know that the comic, I haven't read the comic book first
to let everybody know
Right, but I know the comic book is like a cult favorite
Alright, so you have this movie that's set in the United States
and you have this league of superheroes
that was formed a while back, like in the 50s, right?
Or something like that
Yeah
And, um
Right, well, it's like an alternate, it's like an alternate, uh, you know
Reality
Yeah
Because in this, in this reality that Watchmen is set in
like Nixon continued on for a second term as president
Right
Um, we, we lost, they lost the Vietnam War
They won, I don't know what happened
They did, they did win because, um, Mr...
God, see, I can't remember
Sorry, I can't even remember
Who? Oh, Dr. Manhattan
Dr. Manhattan, right, yeah, yeah, Dr. Manhattan
Dr. Manhattan
Because he joined the war
Exactly, right
And so they won, they won in Vietnam
and it ushered in, like, a lot of popularity for Nixon
Um, the story is, is the good part about the movie
It's one of the, you know, the really strong points about the movie
because behind the, the story, there's, there's a whole comic book series
Right, right, right
It's based on a comic book
Right, Jay, you've also, you've also seen the movie, right?
I have
Did you enjoy it?
I did
Did you understand it?
Did you, like, watch, see the comic beforehand or was it the first time you were exposed to it?
Um, yeah, it was the first time I was exposed to it
I didn't know that it was a comic beforehand
Until now?
And, um, yeah, well I saw it the first time and I was like
I have no idea what just happened
and so I walked it a second time and understood it quite a bit better
You watched it twice
I did
Yeah, I've heard that you should watch that movie twice
Yeah
I kind of understand it better
I watched the, I watched the second half of it twice
Alright, so basically you have this group of superheroes that were formed a while back
and then as they get older they kind of just become regular civilians
because people start kind of complaining about the superheroes helping out society
and saying that they should just let the police do the work
because I think they were, like, causing more harm than good, right?
Well, yeah, that's, that's one of the, the really interesting parts of the story
is that it's kind of one of the only comic books that portrays heroes in a real human kind of light
Like, all of the heroes in the Watchmen series have, like, have, like, they're either psychotic
like, uh, like Roarzak, I mean his name even is Roarzak
I mean, so, you know, it has a lot of mental institution connotations
Um, or, or, you know, they just have a lot of flaws
Um, so it's
Because they're people in the end, they're not really, like, aliens
Right, and even the very, you know, right, and then even in the very end there's
You know, there's, it deals a lot with, um, you know, human philosophy and giving up
You know, and trading off a lot of people's lives for supposed benefit
I mean, it's, there, it's not a perfect universe
Right
Which is nice to see in a movie because it's, it's actually maybe closer to reality than others
And the movie did, well, what was your favorite character?
Man, I mean, I think I like Joker a lot
Joker?
The comedian, the comedian, the comedian
Oh, the comedian
The comedian
I feel like I'm just doing such an injustice to this movie
You are
Because I've, I've only, I've watched it and then there's a huge cult following
I've never even read the comic book, but I, but yeah
Joker is, the comedian
The comedian is good
Alright, what about you Jay, did you have, like, a favorite superhero?
Um
Of that movie
Uh, yeah, my favorite was, um, I don't, I'm definitely not saying his name right, but
Roarzak
Roarzak, isn't it Roarzak
It's like the Roarzak test
Roarzak or Roarzak
Roarzak, I don't know, but it's based on that test, isn't it?
Right, right, cause it's
Cause it's, yeah, his mask keeps on changing
Like, it's the ink, the ink blot test
Yeah, I thought he was kind of disfigured or something under it
So when they took off his mask I was like, oh, he's just a normal guy
He's just like a little skinny Irish guy
Yeah, he was
Uh, definitely I think my favorite was Doctor Manhattan
Cause he was like the most all mighty powerful
So obvious
Yeah
I mean it was cool because the guy was not only freakishly strong and like amazing, but
he was also very, very intelligent
Right
So, and he was doing a lot of experiments and a lot of things for humans
But of course the interesting part was that he was like a physicist, right?
And as in many cases throughout history he was being used by the US government to build like weapons and prototypes of things
Sure, yeah
To help the defense
Yeah, the military industrial complex at work
Yeah, exactly
So it was an interesting movie
I guess the military industrial, not educational complex
Yeah
In the movie also the ending was different from the comic book ending
Really?
From what I understand
Oh really?
So yeah, I guess a lot of the people who are following the movie or like the cult of
The people that actually follow the comic book weren't really pleased with the ending from what I understand
Hmm
Yeah
What was the guy's name?
The millionaire guy
The pretty boy
Can't remember his name
Do you remember his name?
Oh no
Can't remember his name?
He's like Bravens and I don't know
They call him by his full name in the movie
Oh you know what I kind of didn't like was
He doesn't have like a superhero
Was the owl guy
The night owl
Yeah
I didn't really like him
Why not, he's such a nice guy
He is a nice guy but it was like a copy of Batman
Oh you mean his costume design?
And his airplane and everything
Yeah
It was kind of lame I think
Right, I mean he's kind of like the ineffectual
I mean maybe that's part of his character
Because that guy was kind of vapid you know
I mean it was like
You expect most super
Like all of them have flaws
So maybe his flaws that he's just like a boring guy
But he was the one that kind of
Won over the really hot superhero girl in that movie
Yeah
What was her name?
Sometimes girls go for those types of guys
Is that your case Bill?
Of course
Alright so
Vapid, boring, ineffectual
That's you
Alright so overall you would recommend the movie
You would recommend the movie
You would recommend somebody to watch it
I would and I would recommend
You know I would recommend that you
Like Jay said earlier maybe she didn't
I didn't know anything about it either beforehand
But it's a movie that maybe you should read up about a little bit
Maybe if you're into comics you should maybe read the comic first
And then watch the movie
Or the other way around
But I think it is definitely worth
It's worth a watch
Because it's a good story and I think it's important
Alright
What about you Jay, would you recommend it
Did you watch it with friends by yourself?
The first time I watched it with friends
And then the second time around I watched it by myself
But yeah it definitely makes you think
Alright cool
Alright very good
The next show that we're gonna have is about a freaky crazy scary movie that I watched
What's that?
It's a paranormal activity
Oh I heard about that
So be sure to get prepared for that one
Because we're talking about that one next week
It's very scary
You can't get enough for Halloween man
I can
Especially with this movie
This movie was really cool
It's also independent
And it's an independent film so
It makes it a little bit more interesting as well
Alright so if you have any questions
Any doubts you can go on the website
Let's listen before we say goodbye
To a small clip from the movie Watchmen
I am looking at the stars
They're so far away
And their light takes so long to reach us
All we ever see of stars are their old photographs
It's July 1959
Pick it up tomorrow
Okay
75 cents
Okay thank you
Thank you
Gosh Sean I wish you gave us a little notice
I'm sure I made a face
Oh no no
I'm sure that you'll look beautiful
Her name is Janie Slater
She is a physicist
Like me
I am 30 years old
We were introduced by a good friend of mine from college, Wally Weaver
It is February 12, 1981
Wally dies of cancer
Of which they now say I am the cause
For the first time
The accident awaits me
Oh I'll catch up with you guys
I think I left my watch inside
Hey, let's just wait a second
Cross the room to the intrinsic field center
I find my watch
When I get to the door
Wally is turning white
The program's locked in
I can't override the time loss
I am terrified
John
Sorry John
But I can't
Hey don't leave me
Well it's 1959 when I'm introduced to Janie
She buys me a beer
The first time a woman has done this for me
As she passes me the cold perspiring glass
Our fingers touch
Now it's just a question
Of reassembling the components in the correct sequence
I feel fear
For the last time
A token funeral is held
There is nothing to bury
Janie frames the snapshot
It's the only photograph of me anyone has
A circulatory system is seen
By the perimeter fence
A few days later
A partially muscled skeleton stands in the hallway
And screams for a moment before vanishing
Is that it?
Nations around the world still relink from this morning's announcement
Possibly the most significant event in recent history
We repeat
The superman exists
And he is American
Alright we're back
So that was a small clip with Dr. Manhattan
His voice is really awesome
Yeah, I actually, I'm with you Mark
That guy's pretty awesome
Do you know what the symbol on his chest represents?
No
It's a hydrogen atom
Because he's the power
He's the atomic power man
Kind of
He's like a god-like figure
He is
He can change forms
He can transport himself
He can sleep on Mars and be all right
What's his fault then?
I guess we're talking about all the different faults
That he's lost the sensitivity of the human touch
He's insensitive
He's become very cold
He's cold to humanity
Because he's almost not human anymore
I'm gonna be that guy for next Halloween
Alright guys, so that's all the time we have for today
Be sure to come to the website englishpod.com
And we'll see you guys there
Bye